OPIKO ABRAHAM

Kampala, Uganda



abrahamopiko@gmail.com



+256786947100 / +256758068234



linkedin.com/in/abraham-opiko-b20101190

Summary

I am a passionate Software Engineer who strives to work and deliver adequate services at work and am enthusiastic about learning and working with trending technologies. I am flexible in a work environment and passionate about hard work and give maximum respect to my employer in my bid to attain professional success. I have experience of more than three years in software development.

Experience



Software Engineer

Busitema University

Aug 2019 - Present (2 years 7 months +)

Key Responsibilities

- Developing Frontend of web-based systems
- Developing Backend of web-based systems
- Building and Deploying Web Applications;

Core Tools

JavaScript, JQuery, MySQL, Django, Wagtail, Python

Software Engineer

SWB ART & Technical Skills Uganda

Apr 2019 - Jul 2019 (4 months)

Key Responsibilities

- Developed Frontend of web-based systems for clients.
- Developed Backend of web-based systems for clients.
- Built and Deploying Websites for clients.;

Core Tools

• JavaScript, JQuery, MySQL, PHP, Laravel.

Software Engineer

Xclusive Internship @BU

May 2019 - Jul 2019 (3 months)

Key Responsibilities

- Built Front and Backend web-based systems for different clients.
- Built and Deployed Websites for different clients using WordPress.
- Trained students on web design and development.

Core Tools

HTML5, CSS 3, Bootstrap 4, MySQL, PHP, Python, Django, NodeJS, ReactJS and WordPress.

Education

Busitema University

Bachelor, Computer Engineering

2016 - 2020

I graduated as a computer engineer from Busitema University, majored in software and hardware programming. I did a couple of projects at the University like the currently working and used website (www.busitema.ac.ug) for the University, an online application system, an online examination system and currently building an online voting system for the University.

Bukoyo Senior Secondary School

Uganda Advanced Certificate of Education (UACE), Physics, Mathematics and Economics

2013 - 2015

I completed my high school at Bukoyo secondary school, I studied physics, maths, and economics. I was also a vice president for Educate association, I was able to make liquid soap for the school students and staff.

Licenses & Certifications

Technical Support Fundamentals - Google and offered through Coursera. https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/verify/BVQCQG37AA4G

Artificial Intelligence (AI) Programming with Python - African App Launchpad 2019 offered through Udacity

https://confirm.udacity.com/AA5CDLR9

Skills

api • javascript • php • python • React.js • Node.js • GitHub • SQL • NoSQL • Django

Honors & Awards

Trainer of the week - Africa Code Week 2019

Nov 2019

Selected to train students in various schools to learn programming in Eastern Uganda in 2019.

Trainee of the month - eMobilis Mobile Technology Institute 2019 offered by Google Oct 2019

Awarded the Certificate of completion on Basic Digital Skills Training sponsored by Google.